# MELISSA FOX

## Full Stack Software Developer

973-943-8447 melissa.caitlin.fox@gmail.com

### **Summary**

Versatile and dedicated software developer experienced in both front- and back-end development for content and inventory management, ticketing, and live event experience applications. Works well with technical and non-technical teams to accomplish project targets while optimizing designs for a premiere user experience.

### **Work Experience**

#### Full Stack Developer Aloompa (CUE Audio)

April 2022 - Present

- · Collaborate with a small and agile team to develop SAAS content management software for music, sports, conference, and community-focused live events across the world, including Coachella, CrossFit Games, VidCon and Byron Nelson.
- Leverage AWS services Including AppSync, DynamoDB, Lambda, Cognito, and S3 to build robust and scalable applications.
- · Utilize Typescript and event-driven serverless architecture to optimize code quality and maintainability.
- · Lead developer for the migration of a legacy ticketing platform into a monorepo, involving updating code and data structures, and developing enhanced features for the new platform, including integrations with Square Payments and Twilio.
- · Build and maintain reporting dashboard and data visualization tools for both internal and Google Analytics data.
- Continually enhance the platform's self-service capabilities In collaboration with product and design teams.
- Primary stack includes Typescript, React.js, Node.js, GraphQL, VTL

#### Software Developer Apprentice Nashville Software Schhool

September 2021-March 2022

- Developed full-stack web-based applications using JavaScript, React, Python, Django, HTML, CSS, and SQL.
- · API testing using Postman and Swagger
- · Wrote integration tests and Django template reports
- · Deployed applications using Heroku
- Remote group project collaboration in a scrum agile environment

#### Academic Tutor Stoke Education

July 2018-November 2022

- Provided ACT/SAT exam prep tutoring for college-bound students.
- Prepared lower-grade students for private school entrance exams (ISEE).
- · Provided general academic tutoring for students of all ages and brought struggling students up to level with comprehensive teaching and practice strategies.
- · Promoted development of critical thinking skills and effective study habits in addition to course content.

#### Lead Carnivore Keeper Nashville Zoo

June 2017-September 2021

- · Assisted in supervising keeper staff in the care and husbandry of all animals within the Carnivore Department.
- · Managed staff schedule and coordinated cross-department scheduling for animal procedures, transports, and events.
- · Actively involved in all aspects of animal care within department, i.e. training, record keeping, managing breeding programs, education.

#### **Education**

#### Full Stack Web Development 2022

Nashville Software School

#### Bachelor of Arts In Biology 2012

Elmira College

#### Skills

- Javasscript
- Typescript
- Amazon Web Services
- GraphQL
- Velocity Template Langauge

- API Design and Development
- React.js
- Next.js
- Git
- GitHub
- JIRA
- Confluence
- New Feature Development
- Python
- Django
- SQL
- NoSQL
- DynamoDB

- AWS AppSync
- AWS S3
- AWS Lambda
- AWS CloudWatch
- AWs Cognito
- AWS CloudFormation